this exercise
asks us to get rid of 11 which is the
last element in our array
and append a 3.
so just to look at our current array
we'll run our code and we see our array
contains numbers
0 through 11.
i'm going to jump into irb to
demonstrate
a method we can use to remove the last
element of an array
so here in irb i'm going to just create
a small array of integers 1 2 and 3.
now if i invoke the array pop method
on this array it returns the last
element of the array
but that's not all it does it
destructively removes that last element
so now if i examine what our array is
currently
we see it contains only the elements 1
and 2.
our last element 3 was removed
destructively when we called pop on the
array
it is important to remember that pop
returns the removed element
rather than the array itself
so hopping back to our text editor
we can remove 11 from the end of our
array
by calling pop on the array
the next step here is to append a three
and again we can do that either using
the shovel operator to append
or using the array push method which
would look like this
[Music]
now let's run our code again printing
our array
and we expect to see that our array
contains integers
0 through ten and that the last element
is
three
you